Hello, this is JB, I'm with Austin Homebrew Supply in Austin, Texas.
Talking to you today about equipment and process and ingredients that go into making your own beer at your own home.
Or wine, or cider, or socky.
You got a lot of different things you can make here.
So.
One of the things you want to do at the end of, or during the process of either making beer, especially beer making, or even wine, is you need to rack or transfer, we had some strange terminology here, but, racking means to transfer from point A to point B.
So, especially in beer making a lot of time you're moving hot liquids from one point to another, especially if you want to take a hot liquid from a low point and take it to a higher point.
Well it's going to be a real difficult to pick up a boiling hot container of liquid and move it.
So, so, that being said, we carry food grade pumps that, the reason they're food grade is, there's a space between where the motor hosing is, the actual pump drive with the magnetic drive between, so.
There's a complete difference between the motor, and where the actual liquid comes through.
Subsequently it's food grade.
In other words, there's no way that any kind of oil and or internal petroleums or lubricants can contact the beer or wine that you're moving through here.
So.
These guys are called food grade pumps.
They're made by a company called March, and these guys do a great job of moving hot, boiling wort or beer from point A to point B without you having to pick up big kettles full of hot broiling liquid.
So.
Food grade pumps really come in handy when you're brewing.